EMANUEL TEODOR BLAGA

Personal Profile

I am an experienced automotive engineer with more than 10 years of experience both at OEM manufacturers as well as suppliers with in-depth knowledge and expertise in optics, BIW ,plastics design and manufacturing processes, and in the same time possessing considerable management experience such as group leader, project manager or leader of design and development department.

Work Experience

03/04/2019 - present

GEELY DESIGN, GOTHENBURG, SE

Position: Studio engineer

Description:

Working closely with the Designers, Clay modellers, CAS modellers to deliver specific studies to support the successful delivery of the future production product.

Assisting the studio with the creation of physical models to ensure the accuracy of key criteria Concept development with CATIA V5

CAD version management via Teamcenter

Feasibility study for exterior trim parts

Requirements transfer between studio and engineering

Organizing specific topic meetings with stakeholders such as engineering, suppliers etc

Components owned: Vehicle front end and rear end, hood, front bumper and ornaments, front lights, front fenders, rear lights, tailgate, rear bumper, rear spoiler

21.10.2013-29/03/2019

JAGUAR LAND ROVER, GAYDON, UK

Position: Senior lead engineer exterior trim

Description:

Supporting **Studio engineer** for concept design work involving generating and analysing CATIA v5 Geometry to create compatible and clear concepts between supplier engineering and Design, generating and analysing CATIA v5 Geometry to support study items and decision matrix Using Team Centre to develop CAD models using CATIA v5

Validate surface feasibility loops by analysing package, regulation and a range of CAE simulation results such as photometry, thermal analysis and tolerance stack analysis.

Validate and check alignment between PDS and OXO product attributes specifications Light function homogeneity renderings evaluation based on studio proposals

GD&T datum and tolerance concept proposal and validation, tolerance stack calculations, cut planes and measurement point's validation.

Measurement jig concept validation

SCSS (Special key characteristics) validation for supplier critical measurement, manufacturing key characteristics (torque, speed, bar code scan), Body in White critical characteristic (measurement of datum contact points, pitch between different critical panels)

Dimensional Variation analysis (DVA) offer inputs for study of factors contribution analysis and feasible tolerance values.

3D modelling with CATIA V5 Part/ Assembly Design and Generative Shape Design for clearance analysis, section analysis and modification proposal

Siemens UGS Teamcenter for CAD versions release and freeze management

WERS concern release for part attribute specification in manufacturing system such as part number, revision level, piece price, tooling budget, alerts etc.

GRADE reviews support for electronics development validation against JLR best practices and design rules standards such as EMC targets, thermal management, IP protection, schematic analysis, block diagram analysis and inrush currents analysis

Device transmittal (DT) database specifications for connector type (wet or dry), pin out, nominal operated current A/voltage V, inrush current/voltage, inrush current time.

Engineering change request (ECR) for electrical change management

DV/PV Vehicle design validation through IBM Rational DOORS and RTC for test configuration and applicability analysis as well as performing vehicle test such as night drives for lighting performance assessment, water tightness (hose, high pressure washer, and dust), and vehicle vibration test for material cracks, NVH squeak and rattle.

eAPQP deliverables tracking and assessment along with the supplier technical assistance (STA) engineer from Phase 0 (PDS, RFQ) phase up to Phase 3 (PPAP and PSW) deliverables

System engineering for electrical integration of BCM(Body Control module)- IPMA (front vison camera) – HCM (Headlamp control module) through validating electrical architecture, software requirements and version management (EIS files, CCF Car Configuration Files) to deliver headlamp features such as AHBA (Automatic High Beam Assist), AHB (Adaptive High Beam, 4 shadows, town/city/highway mode), matrix LED through Pixel technology, Animated functions such as wake-up/shut down animated sequence, direction indicator animation sequence, Sign Post dimming, laser LED, etc.

Supplier management through weekly and punctual PMST meetings, meeting minutes, focusing on quality issues, feasibility study validation, CAD readiness, GD&T assessment, time planning review for deliverables such as off tool parts, modification, tooling readiness and D&D budgets tracking and validation along with piece price tracking, negations for ongoing design change request (DCR) using systems such as Redbook, etracker and WERS concern release

Problem solving using AIMS2 system to record and track problem solving using Six sigma yellow belt learned good practices

Cost Management, tracking and reporting of all costs associated with the component piece, tooling and engineering development.

Risk management using DFMEA and Lessons learned process to identify risks, track and record actions for reducing risks frequency, occurrence and criticality. Prepare and review lessons learned document for each project milestone to be reviewed by centre of competence (CoC) exterior trim team.

Components owned: Headlamps, Rear lamps, CHMSL, Rear/Front fog lamps, front bumper mounting brackets

Interfering components: Bumpers front and rear, bumper brackets, hood, side wing panel, front end carrier, tailgate, body side panel, exterior trim finishers

Projects: Landover Discovery 17 model year, Jaguar XF 16 and 21 model year, Jaguar F-Pace 21 model year

Software experience:

ENOVIA, CATIA V5, SAP, GPDS, FPDS, PPAP, AIMS, WERS, PACN, Team Centre, Visview Mockup, Digibuck, RADS, IBM Rational DOORS, Microsoft Project, MS Office, MS Excel macros, FMEA, Six Sigma Yellow Belt, Smart sheets, eAPQP, Device Transmittal (DT)

20.08.2012-18.10.2013 *VALEO, LE HAINAUT, BELGIUM*

Position: PROJECT MANAGER VOLVO PROJECTS

Description: Project manager on Volvo projects and MAN projects for products development such as CHMSL, FOG Lamps for new VOLVO XC 90 and MAN Phevos Head lamps. I was as well responsible for developing new technology projects such as powerful 1 multichip LED fog lamps, laser welding processes, precise tolerance assembly and adjustment.

Responsible for project budgets up to 2 million Euros to meet cost and budget targets.

Weekly project status reporting to management on QCT

Responsible for leading two teams of 6 members each.

Responsible for new projects RFQ's

Achievements:

Raised the project profitability form 18% to 33%

Milestones secured on time with recovery action plans

Successfully managed P2 (Research and development) project when technical feasibility was critical

Successfully managed 6 simultaneous projects

Software experience:

CATIA V5, Matrix, SAP, Microsoft Project, MS Office, MS Excel macros,

01.10.2010 - 28.07.2012 HELLA, TIMISOARA, RO

Position: DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Description: Coordination of Time to Marketing activities such as new projects or engineering management projects by weekly design and project review meetings.

I was responsible for resources planning, department profitability as well as creating the department strategy and roadmap.

Achievements:

Increased the Design and Development Headcount from 11 up to 24 persons

Managing budgets up to 3 million EURO

Driving up to 12 simultaneous projects

Creating the Department fit for growth strategy

Driving design to cost activities that led to 150.000/ year savings

Implement the electronics hardware development competences strategy

Implement new technologies such as glowing body, edge-light and active PCBA for LED Technology

Implement local laboratory function

Implement local optics engineering function

Design processes according to the Corporate Management System

Software experience:

CATIA V5, SAP, Lotus Notes, MS Office, Helios optical simulation software, Cadence Allegro

RENAULT, BUCHAREST, RO

15.01.2007 - 29.09.2010

Position: PMST LEADER / MODULE LEADER

Description: Part development for Headlamps, rear lamps, CHMSL, Fog lights and interior light for DACIA SANDERO and DACIA DUSTER projects

Series production part development manager for car seats, safety equipment's, wiping and washing and lights systems for all DACIA products range

Responsible for leading suppliers meet the master time plan and supplier time plan reviews.

Responsible for weekly PMST meetings with suppliers

Responsible for leading team and supplier to achieve QCD targets

Management project status reporting

Managing and DFEMA/PFMEA

Risk management, tracking quality issues AIMS

Suppliers CAD data review and release

Responsible for PSW (Product Submission Warrant) and assuring the comply with all technical standards

Managing and planning the homologation process

Managing supplier trough production's ramp-up

Responsible for high hurts and lessons learned process following the project experience feedback and proposing new standards and best practices;

Exterior trim parts owned:

Headlights, Rearlights, washing wiper mechanism

Interior trim parts owned:

Front and Rear seats, Airbags, Steering wheel airbag cover, airbag computer module, restraints and interior I

Achievements:

Savings up to 1.5 mio Euros trough VA/VE activities

Managed a team of 10 people

Milestone targets achieved by more than 95% rate against 85% target

Milestone timing targets achieved with no delays

Outstanding evaluations with very positive results in achieving targets

Software experience:

CATIA V5, GDG, SIGNE, LUP, ANPQP, MS Project

01.09.2003 - 30.10.2004 COMAU ROMANIA, RO

Position: CAD DESIGNER BIW TOOLING

Description: Design 3D & 2D metal sheet clamping units in AutoCAD and CATIA V4 for the automotive industry

Achievements

Key Skills / IT & Software Experience

Resource management, engineering manager, plastic and electronics knowledge, project management, ISO certification experience, budget management, VA/VE, lighting systems, car seats, passive safety system

GPDS / FPDS / PPAP / AIMS/ WERS/ PACN/ CATIA V5 / GDG, SIGNE / LUP / ANPQP / MS Project / SAP / Lotus Notes / MS Office/ Helios optical simulation software / Cadence Allegro / Team Centre Visview Mockup / DigiBuck / RADS /DOORS / Microsoft Project / MS Office / MS Excel macros / Python / Javascript/ HTML5/ CSS

Education (if applicable)

10/2006 – 07/2008 UNIVERSITY OF ORADEA

Master in Marketing and Business Communication

10/2000 – 07/2005 [UNIVERSITY OF ORADEA]

Bachelor degree Mechanical Engineer

Additional Information

- Driving licence CAT B
- Languages spoken : English, Romanian, French, German
- Willing to commute or relocate

Interests

 Formula 1, Cars, Motorcycles, History, Archaeology, Reading, Computer science, Machine Learning, coding

References are available on request.